Estelle Ishigo papers, 1941-1957
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Ishigo papers., 1941-1957.; 8.5 linear ft.
  - Correspondence and Documents., (.5 linear ft.)
    - Correspondence re the Ishigos' postwar evacuation claims., 1952-1954.; (32 items) (Box 79, Folder 1)
      - Letter, 1953 December 10, to Honorable Cecil R. King, Washington, D.C., Date Created: December 10, 1953.; Item no. 22; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter regarding Mrs. Ishigo's claim, as a Caucasian spouse, for compensation for loss as a result of internment. Mention is made of introducing a bill of legislation on Mrs. Ishigo's behalf.
      - Letter, 1954 March 2, Washington, D.C. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Los Angeles, Calif., Date Created: March 2, 1954.; Item no. 23; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letterhead: Japanese American Citizens' League, Suite 51, 1737 H. Street, Northwest, Washington D.C.
        Letter regarding Mrs. Ishigo's Japanese evacuation claim case and the introduction of legislation to support her case.
      - Letter, 1954 March 19, Washington, D.C. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Los Angeles, Calif., Date Created: March 19, 1954.; Item no. 24; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter from the U.S. Department of Justice acknowledging receipt of Mrs. Ishigo's letter detailing her efforts to obtain further compensation for the Japanese evacuation claim filed by Arthur Ishigo. The U.S. Department of Justice states they do not intend to change their previous decision to deny further compensation.
      - Letter, 1954 March 27, Los Angeles, Calif. to Senator Thomas H. Kuchel, Washington, D.C., Date Created: March 27, 1954.; Item no. 25; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter accompanying a fact sheet detailing the Ishigos' long struggle with government officials for recognition of their Japanese evacuation claim.
      - Letter, 1954 April 5, to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Los Angeles, Calif., Date Created: April 5, 1954.; Item no. 26; (1 p.; 27 x 21 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letterhead = United States Senate. Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.
        Letter written to acknowledge receipt of Mrs. Ishigo's letter regarding her Japanese evacuation claim.
      - Letter, 1954 June 23, to Honorable Samuel Wm. Yorty, Washington, D.C., Date Created: June 23, 1954.; Item no. 27; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter inquiring about intentions to introduce a bill of legislation concerning the compensation rights of non-Japanese spouses in Japanese evacuation claims.
      - Letter, 1954 June 23, Los Angeles, Calif. to Senator Thomas H. Kuchel, Washington, D.C., Date Created: June 23, 1954.; Item no. 28; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
      - Letter, 1954 June 23, Los Angeles, Calif. to Mr. Mike M. Masaoka, Washington, D.C., Date Created: June 23, 1954.; Item no. 29; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
      - Letter, 1954 June 28, Washington, D.C. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Los Angeles, Calif., Date Created: June 28, 1954.; Item no. 30; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter responding to Mrs. Ishigo's letter of June 23, 1954. Mr. Masaoka states that he knows of no legislation being introduced to extend benefits to non-Japanese spouses. He also states that the Japanese American Citizens League has not taken a position on the matter.
        This letter was cc'd to: Mr. Tats Kushida, Pacific Southwest Regional Director, JACL, Mr. Masao W. Satow, National Director, JACL and Mr. George J. Inagaki, National President, JACL.
      - Letter, 1954 June 30, Washington, D.C. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Los Angeles, Calif., Date Created: June 30, 1954.; Item no. 31; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter written to acknowledge receipt of Mrs. Ishigo's letter of June 23, 1954.
      - Letter, 1954 June 30, Washington, D.C. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Los Angeles, Calif., Date Created: June 30, 1954.; Item no. 32; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter from California state Senator Thomas H. Kuchel stating that he must decline to introduce private legislation on Mrs. Ishigo's behalf.
      - Letter, 1954 August 2, Washington, D.C. to Mrs. Estelle Ishigo, Los Angeles, Calif., Date Created: August 2, 1954.; Item no. 33; (3 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter from Gene H. Miller, secretary to California Congressman Sam Yorty. Enclosed is a copy of a letter from the U.S. Department of Justice concerning the Ishigos' Japanese evacuation compensation claim.
      - Letter, 1954 Nov. 29, to Chairman, House Judiciary Sub-Committee, Washington, D.C., Date Created: November 29, 1954.; Item no. 35; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 1)
        Letter written by J.Allan Frankel, on the Ishigos' behalf, concerning hearings on the Japanese Evacuation Claims Act of 1948.
        A handwritten note addressed to Estelle Ishigo appears at the bottom of the page.
    - Records, documents and other materials relating to the Ishigos' evacuation claims, ca. 1949-1954.., (18 items) (Box 79, Folder 2)
      - Draft letter, Ishigo evacuation fact sheet., n.d.; Item no. 1; (3 p.; 43 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 2)
        Draft of a letter detailing the facts surrounding the Ishigo's evacuation in 1941. It appears this letter was written to be sent out to numerous government officials to support the Ishigo's Japanese evacuation claim for compensation.
      - Notes calculating the value of lost property., Date Created: between 1942 and 1948.; Item no. 2; (6 p.; 21 x 13 cm. (sizing varies)) (Box 79, Folder 2)
        Handwritten notes calculating the value of lost property in preparation for filling out a claim form from the U.S. Department of Justice for reparations.
      - Draft notes of answers for U.S. Department of Justice claim form., n.d.; Item no. 3; (3 p.; 26 x 16 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 2)
        Handwritten notes of numbered answers corresponding to questions appearing on the U.S. Department of Justice's claim form for damage to or loss of real or personal property by a person of Japanese ancestry.
      - Claim for damage to or loss of real or personal property by a person of Japanese ancestry., Date Created: April 27, 1949.; Item no. 4; (4 p.; 34 x 21 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 2)
        Claim form filled out by Arthur Shigeharu Ishigo to request adjudication of a claim resulting from his evacuation in 1941. Includes a description of the property involved and a statement of damage and loss resulting from evacuation.
      - Draft letter, 1954 Feb. 7, Los Angeles, Calif., Date Created: February 7, 1954.; Item no. 5; (2 p.; 33 x 22 cm. plus 1 p.; 24 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 2)
        Letter regarding the Ishigos' Japanese evacuation claim for compensation for loss and damages.
      - Adjudication of the claim of Julius Down., Date Created: February 26, 1953.; Item no. 6; (7 p.; 34 x 21 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 2)
        Text of the conclusion to the Japanese evacuation claim of Julius Down.
      - Draft letter, statutory construction., n.d.; Item no. 7; (2 p.; 33 x 22 cm plus 4 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 2)
        Draft of a letter detailing the events and circumstances surrounding the Ishigo's forced evacuation. The letter appears to have been written to provide justification for their claim for compensation for loss and suffering.
      - Draft letter, Los Angeles, Calif. to Mike Masaoka, Washington, D.C., Item no. 8; (1 p.; 49 x 22 cm. plus 1 p.; 41 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 2)
        Draft of a letter written to Mike Masaoka, Executive Secretary of the Japanese American Citizens League, regarding the Ishigo's Japanese American evacuation claim.
      - Fact sheet, 1954 February 15., Date Created: February 15, 1954.; Item no. 9; (3 p.; 33 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 2)
        Draft of a letter detailing the facts and circumstances surrounding the Ishigo's forced evacuation.
      - Resolution regarding the Evacuation Claims Act of 1948., n.d.; Item no. 10; (2 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 2)
        Typewritten resolution regarding compensation for losses incurred by non-Japanese persons as a result of internment. The resolution requests that legislation be drafted to amend the provisions of the Evacuation Claims Act of 1948.
      - Return receipt, 1953 July 29, Washington, D.C. to Mrs. Arthur Ishigo, Los Angeles, Calif., Date Created: July 29, 1953.; Item no. 11; (1 postcard; 8 x 13 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 2)
        Return receipt of an insured parcel sent to Hon. Herbert Brownell, Jr. by Estelle Ishigo.
      - Address notes., n.d.; Item no. 12; (1 p.; 10 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 2)
        Typewritten notes listing the addresses of local and national political figures Estelle Ishigo contacted regarding her husband's claim for reparations.
      - Sample claim form for damages., Date Created: 1949.; Item no. 14; (4 p.; 36 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 2)
        Copy of a claim form issued by the United States Department of Justice to be filled out for practice purposes. The claim is for damage to or loss of real or personal property by a person of Japanese ancestry.
      - Evacuee loss survey, instructions for interviewers., n.d.; Item no. 15; (6 p.; 36 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 2)
        Typed instructions for interviewers conducting surveys of losses incurred by persons evacuated in 1942.
      - American Council on Race Relations suggestions for interviewer., n.d.; Item no. 16; (4 p.; 36 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 2)
        Suggestions for interviewers collecting information from Japanese-Americans who were evacuated from their homes by military order in 1942.
      - Letter, to claimants under the Evacuation Claims Act of July 2, 1948., Item no. 17; (2 p.; 33 x 21 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 2)
        Form letter sent to claimants under the Evacuation Claims Act, offering expedited claims processing in exchange for a lesser compensation amount.
      - Department of Justice, Claims Division, Evacuation Claims, Affidavit., n.d.; Item no. 22; (2 p.; 34 x 21 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 2)
        Partially completed Affidavit regarding the Ishigo's Japanese American evacuation claim.
      - Postcard, 1950 August 3, Washington, D.C. to Mr. Arthur Shigeharu Ishigo, Hawthorne, Calif., Date Created: August 3, 1950.; Item no. 24; (1 postcard; 8 x 13 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 2)
        Form postcard acknowledging receipt of the claim Mr. Ishigo filed with the U.S. Department of Justice.
    - Manuscripts and drafts for Estelle Ishigo's short story, Lone Heart Mountain., (44pp., 5 items) (Box 79, Folder 3)
      - Lone Heart Mountain., n.d.; Item no. 3; (44 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 3)
        Typed manuscript of Estelle Ishigo's autobiographical narrative describing her internment experience.
      - Lone Heart Mountain draft., Item no. 4; (41 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 3)
        Typed manuscript with handwritten edits of Estelle Ishigo's autobiographical narrative "Lone Heart Mountain."
      - Letter, 1955 November 9, Los Angeles, Calif. to Joseph Friedman, New York, N.Y., Date Created: November 9, 1955.; Item no. 5; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 3)
        Typewritten letter to Joseph Friedman of the Writers' Workshop in New York notifying him that Estelle Ishigo has sent him a copy of her "Lone Mountain" manuscript.
    - Manuscripts for her essay, A Treatment for Cancer (at Temple Hospital)., February 1958.; (22pp. Carbon and photocopies, 2 items) (Box 79, Folder 4)
      - A treatment for cancer (at Temple Hospital)., Date Created: February 1958.; Item no. 1; (22 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 4)
        Typed manuscript of Estelle's narrative account of her husband's battle with cancer and his subsequent death.
    - Unfinished manuscript for To Protect the Innocent., n.d.; (14pp., 1 item) (Box 79, Folder 5)
      - To protect the innocent., n.d.; Item no. 1; (14 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 5)
        Unfinished typewritten manuscript of a short story about a Japanese American boy during the period of evacuation and internment.
    - Manuscripts and drafts for her short articles submitted to the Mystic: The Vision of a Cave., September 1954; October 1954.; (2pp., 2pp., 1p., 8 items) (Box 79, Folder 6)
      “A Ball of Light”; “The Cat and the Ghost”.
      - The vision of a cave., Date Created: September 25, 1954.; Item no. 1; (2 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 6)
        Typed manuscript of a short story submitted to "Mystic" magazine.
      - Letter, 1954 September 25, Los Angeles, Calif. to Mr. Ray Palmer, Amherst, Wisconsin., Date Created: September 25, 1954.; Item no. 2; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 6)
        Letter to the editor of "Mystic" magazine accompanying two short stories sent for publication.
      - A ball of light., Date Created: September 25, 1954.; Item no. 3; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 6)
        Typed manuscript of a short story submitted to "Mystic" magazine for publication.
      - The cat and the ghost., Date Created: October 23, 1954.; Item no. 4; (2 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 6)
      - The cat and the ghost, draft., Date Created: October 23, 1954.; Item no. 5; (2 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 6)
        Typed manuscript with handwritten edits.
      - The ball of light, draft., Date Created: September 25, 1954.; Item no. 6; (1 p.; 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 6)
      - The cat and the ghost, draft., Item no. 8; (2 p.: 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 6)
      - Woman carrying pail., n.d.; Item no. 10; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 21 x 13 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 6)
        Pencil sketch of a woman carrying a pail.
      - Handwritten draft for a play, Early Dawn., Item no. 1; (5pp., 1 item, 28 x 22 cm.) (Box 79, Folder 7)
        Pencil draft of a play about a boy and girl living in a Japanese American relocation center.
    - Handwritten notes and unfinished drafts for her projected short stories, essays and articles., (approximately 50 items) (Box 79, Folder 8-9)
  - Miscellany and Published Materials., ( .5 linear ft.
    - Miscellaneous memos and notes kept by Estelle Ishigo., (Approximately 50 items) (Box 80, Folder 1)
      - Diary notes., n.d.; Item no. 4; (10 p.; 23 x 14 cm.) (Box 80, Folder 1)
        It appears that Estelle Ishigo wrote these autobiographical notes over a span of five days spent in a hospital undergoing tests. The year is unknown, but the dates are from Saturday July 24 - Wednesday July 28. The notes are very descriptive and contain hourly entries.
      - Witness log., Date Created: September 21, 1956.; Item no. 33; (2 p.; 29 x 22 cm.) (Box 80, Folder 1)
        Item appears to be a handwritten daily log of suspicious activities occurring in the apartment building lived in by the Ishigos.
      - Paramount notebook., n.d.; Item no. 99; (7 p.; 19 x 13 cm. plus 1 note; 7 x 11 cm. plus 1 note; 18 x 9 cm.) (Box 80, Folder 1)
        Spiral bound notebook with a cover stamped with the Paramount logo and "Paramount Convention June 1939." The notebook contains handwritten poems and notes. Three pages are dated: Aug. 1942, Dec. 1943, and Dec. 17, 1943.
      - Daily account., Date Created: December 2, 1954.; Item no. 100; (21 p.; 15 x 10 cm.) (Box 80, Folder 1)
        Handwritten account of daily occurrences of the disturbing and somewhat violent incidents occurring at the rooming house where Estelle and Arthur were living. Written in a small blue spiral bound notebook; covers a three month period.
    - Incidental financial papers of Estelle Ishigo., ca. 1944-ca. 1956.; (14 pieces) (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - 11 printed programs for various events., ca. 1940s-1952.; (11 items) (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - A collection of various leaflets, pamphlets, and booklets on the Japanese Americans, their evacuation and the relocation camps., ca. 1943-ca. 1946.; (19 items) (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - An incomplete copy of the Far East Photo Review, a magazine printed in New York., n.d.; (1 item) (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Artwork at the Relocation Camp., 1942-1945 & 1954.; (6.5 linear ft.)
    - Handicraft works of Japanese evacuees at relocation camps., (8 pieces) (Box 81)
      - Wood carving with turtle and bird., Date Created: 1944.; Item no. 1; (1 art original: wood; 19 x 34 x 10 cm.) (Box 81)
        Woodcarving depicting a mound with a turtle and a crane. The piece is signed, "1944 Rohwer Ark, HGK.".
      - Vase with stones., n.d.; Item no. 2; (1 art original: cement and stone; 12 x 18 x 10 cm.) (Box 81)
        Rustic vase constructed of cement and stone over an aluminum can.
      - Flatweave., n.d.; Item no. 3; (1 art original: weaving; 40 x 73 cm.) (Box 81)
        Green, blue, and white flatweave.
      - Basket., n.d.; Item no. 4; (1 art original: basket; 9 x 7 x 3 cm.) (Box 81)
        Basket is green, yellow, and red. It appears to be sealed with a kind of protective adhesive.
      - Chopsticks., n.d.; Item no. 5; (chopsticks; 2 x 20 x 1 cm.) (Box 81)
        Wooden chopsticks with Japanese handpainted calligraphy.
      - Chopsticks with red case., n.d.; Item no. 6; (chopsticks; 2 x 20 x 1 cm.) (Box 81)
        Wooden chopsticks with Japanese handpainted calligraphy and red wooden case.
      - Decorative wood plate., n.d.; Item no. 7; (1 art original: wood; 19 x 30 x 2 cm.) (Box 81)
        Handcrafted carved wood plate in the shape of a fish.
      - Wood carving., n.d.; Item no. 8; (1 art original: wood; 24 x 14 x 8 cm.) (Box 81)
        Abstract carved wooden sculpture.
    - A portfolio containing Estelle Ishigo's watercolor sketches at the Heart Mountain Relocation Camp., ca. 1942-ca. 1945.; (30 pieces) (Box 788)
    - A large portfolio containing 7 paintings and pencil sketches of Estelle Ishigo at the Heart Mountain Relocation Camp., ca. 1942-ca. 1945. (Box 788)
    - A large portfolio containing mounted watercolor and pencil sketches of Estelle Ishigo, Heart Mountain and Los Angeles., ca. 1942-ca. 1945 & 1954.; (11 items) (Box 781)
      - A winter evening., Date Created: January 1943.; Item no. 1; (1 art original: watercolor, color; 21 x 33 cm.) (Box 781)
        Watercolor painting depicting barracks at Heart Mountain Relocation Center. Handwritten title beneath painting.
      - Cal seafood fish cannery; trailer camp for evacuees; returned after the war., Date Created: September 1944.; Item no. 2; (1 art original: watercolor, color; 30 x 46 cm.) (Box 781)
        Watercolor painting depicting an outdoor scene at Heart Mountain Relocation Center.
      - Around our place., Date Created: August 1948.; Item no. 3; (1 art original: watercolor, color; 29 x 40 cm.) (Box 781)
        Watercolor painting depicting Japanese American children with a dog outside of a trailer camp. Title handwritten on back of painting.
      - Japanese picnic in Elysian Park., Date Created: August 1954.; Item no. 4; (1 art original: watercolor, color; 39 x 51 cm.) (Box 781)
        Watercolor painting depicting a large group of Japanese Americans having a picnic. Some are depicted playing instruments. Title is handwritten beneath painting.
      - Determination, rain or shine., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 5; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 13 x 17 cm.) (Box 781)
        Black and white drawing depicting a woman standing outside in the rain. Title appears handwritten beneath drawing.
      - Canteen janitress., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 6; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 14 x 14 cm.) (Box 781)
        Black and white pencil drawing depicting a woman sweeping outside of a barrack. Title appears handwritten beneath drawing.
      - Sudden storms., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 7; (1 art original: watercolor, color; 30 x 42 cm.) (Box 781)
        Watercolor painting depicting people in Heart Mountain Relocation Center. It appears that they are running for cover from a storm.
        Title is handwritten in pencil beneath painting. Handwritten note appears at bottom of matte: "Mess hall, latrine, laundry, & barracks.".
      - Japanese American man., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 8; (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 17 x 12 cm.) (Box 781)
        Black and white portrait of a Japanese American man standing against a barbed wire fence. A city skyline is in the distance behind the man.
      - End of day., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 9; (1 art original: watercolor, color; 13 x 21 cm.) (Box 781)
        Watercolor painting depicting Heart Mountain Relocation Center at dusk. Handwritten title beneath painting.
      - The high school., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 10; (1 art original: watercolor, color; 31 x 49 cm.) (Box 781)
        Watercolor depicting a high school with Japanese American children walking and playing outside. Handwritten title beneath painting.
      - No privacy for women and children., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; Item no. 11; (1 art original: watercolor, color; 36 x 26 cm.) (Box 781)
        Watercolor painting depicting Japanese American women and children bathing. Title handwritten in pencil.
    - Lone Heart Mountain, Heart Mountain.., Date Created: September 1942.; (1 art original: oil on canvas; 64 x 76 cm.) (Box 863)
      Oil painting depicting a nude Japanese American family embracing on a mountain top.
    - Gathering coal at Heart Mountain Relocation Camp., Date Created: 1945.; (1 art original: oil on canvas; 51 x 62 cm.) (Box 769)
      Signed on bottom left corner of painting :"Wyo. U.S.A. 1945 Estelle Ishigo" Oil painting depicting a group of Japanese Americans gathering coal in the snow
    - Untitled [Snowstorm], Heart Mountain.., Date Created: February 1944.; (1 art original: watercolor, color; 29 x 39 cm.) (Box 788)
      Impressionistic watercolor painting depicting Heart Mountain Relocation Center barracks in what appears to be a snow storm. The painting is framed.
      Signed Estelle Ishigo 2-44.
    - Untitled (scenery), Los Angeles, 1961..., Date Created: September 1961.; (1 art original: oil on canvas; 36 x 46 cm.) (Box 788)
      Oil painting of a mountain scene at dusk.
    - Untitled, Heart Mountain, Wyoming, ca. 1942.., (28" x 22"); (1 art original: drawing, black and white; 30 x 48 cm.) (Box 783)
      Black and white pencil drawing of Heart Mountain Relocation Center. Crowds of Japanese Americans are depicted standing outside of barracks.
    - A Stormy Day, Heart Mountain, Wyoming, September 1944.., Date Created: September 1944.; (28" x 22"); (1 art original: watercolor, color; 30 x 46 cm.) (Box 783)
    - A Baseball Game, Heart Mountain, Wyoming, Summer 1943.., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; (1 art original: watercolor, color; 26 x 31 cm.) (Box 719)
      Watercolor painting of people playing baseball outdoors in Heart Mountain Relocation Center.
    - Japanese Concentration Camp, Heart Mountain, Wyoming, 1942-1945.., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; (1 art original: watercolor, color; 22 x 29 cm.) (Box 719)
      Impressionistic watercolor painting of Heart Mountain Relocation Center. Handwritten text appears at bottom of painting: "1942-45 Heart Mountain, Wyo. Japanese Concentration Camp." Signed, "Estelle Ishigo."
    - Japanese American woman and child, internees., Date Created: between 1942 and 1945.; (1 art original: watercolor, color; 30 x 27 cm.) (Box 719)
      Watercolor painting depicting a woman holding a small child and standing in front of a barbed wire fence looking out into the horizon. The painting is signed, "Estelle Ishigo."
    - Dust Storm, Heart Mountain, Wyoming, September 4, 1942.., Date Created: ">September 4, 1942.; (1 art original: watercolor, color; 26 x 31 cm.) (Box 719)